BUSINESS PROGRAM MANAGER

Professional Profile

Certified Scrum Master and Lean Six-Sigma Master Black Belt experienced in Program Management, Project Management and Product Development. Demonstrated success in projects encompassing multiple disciplines using problem solving skills and achieve operational excellence. Successful at leading business process improvement projects with an estimated annual COPQ savings of \$ 37M Program Management Project Management Product Lifecycle Mgmt Six Sigma & Lean DMAIC/DMADV Kaizen & VSM Agile & Scrum CI/CD & DevOps Kanban Qualifications

- Data Analysis Tools
- MySQL
- MS ACCESS
- MS EXCEL
- R Programming
- Hadoop
- Minitab
- Lean & Six Sigma Tools
- DFSS, DMAIC
- SPC, DFMEA
- Critical to Quality (CTQ)
- Pareto Analysis
- Value Stream Mapping
- Statistical Data Analysis
- Agile & Scrum Tools
- Rally
- SONAR & Jenkins
- Kanban
- 2
- Harsh Sharma

Experience

Business Program Manager Jan 2013 to Current Microsoft Corporation il/4 Cleveland, OH

- Scrum & Agile Deployment Leading Agile, Scrum, Continuous Integration/Delivery, and DevOps adoption and Onboarding in AT&T
 Strategized and facilitated End to End deployment of Agile, Scrum, CI/CD in 5 pilot software development teams for 20+ projects Defined
 Key Performance Indicators to measure outputs of Agile based projects in terms of Quality, Speed, Cost, and Productivity Developed
 Continuous Delivery dashboard to monitor success of Agile adoption by integrating various metrics from SONAR (Code Coverage, Lines
 of Duplicates, etc.), Jenkins, Maven, HP Quality Center (IST defects etc.) to Post production defect management tool).
- Implemented Agile Earned Value Management (EVM) and core Agile metrics such as Velocity, Iteration Burndown etc to improve predictability and project performance Align Agile input metrics (Velocity, Iteration Burndown etc.) to output metrics (Speed, Quality, Cost) to valuable insights and comparison with Waterfall based projects Designed and orchestrated launch/adoption of Code Evaluation and Code Repository (SONAR & JENKINS) for CI/CD platform Led Agile and Scrum project data integrity effort to eliminate data issues such as null fields, bias etc.

Jan 2007 to Jan 2013

Bickford Senior Living il/4 Saint Charles, IL

- Lean Six Sigma Master Black Belt (IT) & Business Program Manager Spearheaded deployment of companywide initiative Quality
 Management Program for Software Development and Engineering (SD&E) tower resulting in improved operational processes, customer
 satisfaction, and cost reduction of \$25 M+ in 3 years.
- Reported program/project status to executive sponsors for schedule, budget, and quality of all program elements.
- Assisted in instituting employee supported ideation and validation platform resulted in 100+ ideas in area of compliance, Estimation & Finance, SDLC, ITO - VPMO, Helpdesk etc.
- Defined and implemented data driven project selection process using different models such as Net Present Value, Internal Rate of Return.
- Coached and mentored group of black belts, green belts, quality practitioners to achieve operational success in various process improvement projects Lead large, complex cross-functional value stream mapping to identify continuous improvement opportunities Designed and analyzed large data sets related to software development projects to reduce overall cycle time in SD&E (formerly IT BNCS) Analyzed NPS data Digital Life Customers to identify areas of improvements and set action plan to improve customer satisfaction Recruited, trained, and lead 7 Black Belts and achieved significant financial impact with over \$37 million in cost savings from 2007-2013, directly attributable to BB improvement projects utilizing DMAIC, DMADV, and Lean approach Coaching Developed Agile Boot Camp Curriculum (Vision & Funding > Release Planning > Iterations > Closure) Trained 3 Agile Coach, 5 Application Development teams in Scrum & Kanban methodologies Delivered 1600 hours of DMAIC training 2 (3 day) lean training covering kanban, kaizen, PDCA, Change Management Leading SDLC, PMCOE, Six Sigma & Lean forums/societies in IT.

Continuous Improvement Engineer Jan 2004 to Jan 2006 Northern Tool $i^{1/4}$ Merrillville , IN

- Six-Sigma.
- Utilized expertise in Value Stream Mapping, KAIZEN and Lean Manufacturing principles.
- Drove Lean and Six Sigma principles across large, diversified plants employing more than 1000 personnel and running multiple production lines.
- Led and directed three Six Sigma quality projects and cut defects by 50%, realizing a savings of approximately \$100k per project.

Education

Agile Certified Practitioner - PMI (2015) Certified Project Management Professional - PMI (2014) Certified Lean Six Sigma Master Black Belt - AT&T QMS COE 2008

Master of Science, Mechanical Engineering 2005 Cleveland State University Mechanical Engineering

M.S 2002 University of Baroda India

Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering Mechanical Engineering

Skills

Agile, Application Development, approach, budget, CD, Change Management, Coach, Coaching, continuous improvement, cost reduction, costing, customer satisfaction, Data Analysis, Delivery, drivers, Finance, financial, functional, HP, Lean Manufacturing, Lean Manufacturing principles, manufacturing processes, MS ACCESS, MS EXCEL, Minitab, MySQL, personnel, processes, process improvement, procurement, producing, producing 3.5, Programming, Project Management, Quality, Quality Management, SD, Scrum, SDLC, Six Sigma, Six-Sigma, software development, Software Development and Engineering, SPC, validation, Vision